Register of the Edward H. Egbert Papers, 1914-1921
Hoover Institution Archives
Edward H. Egbert Papers
1914-1921
60007
Hoover Institution Archives
1 manuscript box (0.4 linear feet)
Correspondence, notes, clippings, printed matter, and photographs, relating to the Russian Revolution, relief work in Russia, and Ekaterina Breshko-Breshkovskaia. Includes correspondence with E. Breshko-Breshkovskaia and Herbert Hoover.
Egbert, Edward H.
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1960.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
American National Red Cross.; Breshko-Breshkovskaia, Ekaterina Konstantinovna Verigo, 1844-1934.; International relief.; Russia.; Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921.; Soviet Union.; World War, 1914-1918--Civilian relief.; World War, 1914-1918--Russia.; World War, 1914-1918.
- Letters of Dr. Edward H. Egbert from Catherine Breshkovsky. Dr. Egbert was chief surgeon of the American Red Cross detachment to Russia and was Executive Secretary of the Catherine Breshkovsky Russian Relief Fund in New York. (Box-folder 1:1)
  - 1. Feb. 6, 1919 - Majestic Hotel, N.Y. (1 leaf).
  - 2. July 7, 1919 - Aboard S.S. Rochambeau in route to France, (1 leaf). Continued on July 17, 1919, Paris, France.
  - 3. Sept. 14, 1919 - Prague - Bohemia to Mr. Abott (1 leaf).
  - 4. Sept. 1, 1920 - Munkaceva - Karpatorussia, Czechoslovakia.
  - 5. Oct. 4, 1920 - Scilak Hotel. Continued on Oct. 22, 1920 (1 leaf).
  - 6. Oct. 10, 1920 - Mukatchevo, Czechoslovakia (1 leaf).
  - 7. Nov. 17, 1920 - Mukatchevo, Czechoslovakia. Continued on Nov. 18.
  - 8. Dec. 22, 1920 - Uzhorod (4 lv.).
  - 9. Feb. 12, 1920 - Paris - Sanitarium, (2 lv.).
  - 10. Feb. 27, 1920 - Uzhorod, Czechoslovakia (2 lv.).
  - 11. March 18, 1920 - Uzhorod, Czechoslovakia (2 lv.).
  - 12. May 4, 1920 - Uzhorod, Czechoslovakia (2 lv.).
  - 13. June 25, 1920 - Mukachevo (3 lv.).
  - 14. Feb. 2, 1921, Paris, Sanatarium of Dr. Plechanoff (1 lv.).
  - 15. July 25, 1920 - Belki, Czechoslovakia. Continued on July 28 (2 lv.).
  - 16. Feb. 9, 1920 - Paris, Sanitarium (1 leaf).
  - 17. April 2, 1921 - Paris, Sanitarium (1 leaf).
  - 18. May 12, 1921 - Paris, Sanitarium (1 leaf).
  - 19. Undated (1 leaf).
- Copies of letters from and to Mr. and Mrs. Hoover; one letter to Walter L. Brown. (Box-folder 1:2)
- Letter by Egbert (?) to Hiram Johnson, 2 Jan. 1919, carbon copy (5 lv.). (Box-folder 1:3)
- Newspaper clippings on Bolshevik activities in Russia, etc. (c. 1918-1919). (Box-folder 1:4)
- Ibid. (Box-folder 1:5)
- Breshkovsky, Catherine, "A message to the American people" with an introduction by George Kennan (20 pp.) put out by the Russian Information Bureau in the U.S., 1919. (Box-folder 1:6)
- Miscellaneous lecture material, notes, maps, excerpts, etc. (Box-folder 1:7)
- Correspondence regarding applications for Red Cross work in Russia; correspondence with Committee on Public Information (George Creel) regarding establishment of relief organization to Russia; letters from American Russian Chamber of Commerce, etc. (c. 1915-1921). (Box-folder 1:8)
- Material of the American Russian League (1918-1919). (Box-folder 1:9)
- Outgoing correspondence of Egbert (c. 1917-1921) regarding Bolshevism in Russia, Red Cross work in Russia, etc. (Box-folder 1:10)
- Department of State Press Releases regarding revolutionary propaganda aimed at U.S. (including statement by G. Zinoviev.) 29 March (6 lv.) and 1 April 1920 (4 lv.). Also, one copy. (Box-folder 1:11)
- "Catherine Breshkovsky Russian Relief Fund" pamphlet (8 pp.) thermofax (2 copies). (Box-folder 1:12)
- "Russia and the War" by Thomas D. Thacher (14 pp.) thermofax (2 copies). (Box-folder 1:13)
- Thermofax copies of letters possibly from Dr. Egbert dates Oct. 14, 1914 and Sept. 5, 1916 from Moscow. (6 lv.). (Box-folder 1:14)
- Photographs of a Kiev hospital, 1914- (Box-folder 1:15)